So we will see that we can define the embryo in terms of days,
胚を日数で定義できることがわかります。
we can also refer to Carnegie stages, but I will speak in terms of days.
カーネギーについても話せますが、ここでは日数で話します。
When there are synchronicities of phenomena,
現象の同期性がある場合、
such as the closure of the neuropores with the integration of these somites and similar occurrences,
神経孔の閉鎖とこれらの層の統合のようなものがある場合、
we would give you the timing, at the moment of cardiac awareness,
心臓が意識される瞬間など、
such things, we would provide precise points.
そのようなものには正確なポイントを与えます。
Otherwise, we will speak in terms of days or weeks.
そうでなければ、日数または週で話します。
And also, we will provide some notions of size.
また、サイズの概念も少し与えます。
What is truly important for you,
あなたにとって本当に重要なのは、
is the concept of growth.
成長の概念です。
It is to observe that it grows.
それが成長していることを見ることです。
In fact, what needs to be understood,
実際、理解すべきことは、
is that it is a developmental movement.
それが発達的な動きであるということです。
In this approach, it is a movement
このアプローチでは、それは動きであり、
that develops in this manner.
このように発達します。
But it is not a movement that occurs like this.
しかし、それはこのように行われる動きではありません。
This is the difference between what we call
それが、私たちが呼ぶところの
motility and mobility.
モティリティとモビリティの違いです。
One,
一方は、
is an embryonic response,
胚の反応であり、
that is, it follows the movement
つまり、発達の動きに
of development,
従います。
and the other is a movement
もう一方は、呼吸に
linked to respiration,
関連する動きであり、
and which will generate movements,
動きを生み出します。
and the other is a movement further attributed
そしてもう一方は、運動性に関連する動きです。
to motoricity.
運動性に関連する動きです。
You see, one must clearly differentiate.
違いをよく理解する必要があります。
When I move like this, it is very different from
このように動くとき、それは私の肝臓のこの動きとは
this movement at the level of my liver.
非常に異なります。
So, if I want
したがって、組織を再構築したい場合、
to rework a tissue, I restore it
そのモティリティに戻し、その機能的な強さがそこにあることを確認します。
to its motility, and its functional strength, its functional strength is there, you
そこから回復し、それが私たちが行う作業です。
see, that's where
その組織に戻り、
it will recover, and that's the work we do: returning to this tissue so that
「よし、ここで再編成する。モビリティと運動性を取り戻せる」とします。
it can reorganize, regain its mobility, its motricity, you
理解できますか？
understand, it's
常に動きに従うことですが、そこには支点が必要であり、その後、手の中に動きがあることです。
always following the movement, but here you need the fulcrums, and after sensing the movement
私は臓器を治療するのではなく、環境を治療します。
in your hand, I don't treat an organ, I treat an environment.
しかし、時には私の行動はモティリティ、モビリティに影響を与えることがあります。
motricity.
運動性。
And there, regarding mobility, what is it?
では、可動性とは何でしょうか？
The master of mobility is the diaphragm.
可動性の主役は横隔膜です。
That's why we will learn how this diaphragm is built.
だから、この横隔膜がどのように構築されるかを学ぶのです。
One day, he taught me, he said, Marc, one day, you will feel the power in the tissue.
ある日、彼は私に教えてくれました。「マーク、いつか君は組織の中に力を感じるだろう」と。
For me, the concept of power was very intellectual.
私にとって、その力は非常に知的なものでした。
At the same time, intellectually, I tell myself yes, I can understand that there is a kind of...
同時に、知的な面で、私は「ああ、ある種のものを理解できる」と思いました。
When I see an embryo developing, you can imagine the power of it.
発生中の胚を見ると、その力の凄まじさが想像できるでしょう。
It doesn't stop.
それは止まりません。
There's an incredible power; it's astounding.
信じられないほどの力です。
And he tells me sometimes, in the still points, in certain fulcrums, the power is there too.
そして彼は時々、特定の支持点では、その力もそこにあると言いました。
It's incredible; there you can...
それは信じられないほどで、そこであなたは...
Something happens, but you can't create that all the time.
何かが起こるのですが、それを常に作り出すことはできません。
You must try to be present, to have a good connection, and then at some point...
あなたは現在に身を置き、良いつながりを持つように努めなければなりません。そしてある時点で...
the system adjusts
システムが調整される
and then
そして
at one point he tells me
ある時点で彼は私に言いました
it's as if you were on a small boat in the sea
それはまるであなたが海に浮かぶ小さなボートに乗っているかのようだ
you are just in the water
あなたはただ水の中にいる
you don't see it, but beneath you
あなたはそれを見ないが、あなたの下には
there is a whale
クジラがいる
and you are just there, and you feel
そしてあなたはただそこにいて感じる
you suddenly feel
突然感じる
it's somewhat that sensation
それは少しこの感覚に似ている
but observe
しかし見てください
first day
初日
thank you
ありがとう
the small, initial structure that we are,
私たちがいる小さな混乱、
and observe what will happen
そして何が起こるか見てください
at the end of the second month.
2ヶ月目の終わりには。
Observe, in two months,
2ヶ月で見てください、
what is already occurring.
すでに何が起こっているか。
And observe already here,
そしてすでにここを見てください、
at the beginning of the twentieth day,
20日目の初めには、
a form is already taking shape.
すでに形ができています。
Here, the potential for life,
そこに生命の可能性が、
it is present. This is simply
そこにあるのです。これは単に
an ovum
卵子
which has received the genetic heritage
が遺伝情報を受け取ったもので、
from the father,
父親からのものです。
thus, the spermatozoon.
つまり精子です。
The two genetic heritages are in the process of converging.
2つの遺伝的遺産が出会おうとしています。
This is approximately the first image of your life.
これはあなたの人生の最初のイメージとほぼ同じです。
This is still referred to as the Zona Pellucida and nurse cells.
これはまだ透明帯と栄養細胞と呼ばれています。
Another layer of important cells.
もう一層の重要な細胞です。